在叛国罪的条款中:
From the Treaty of the Treason:
为了给13区起义行为赎罪 每个地区每年
In penance for their uprising,each district shall offer up
都要公开"招募"在12-18岁的少年男女作为贡者斗士
a male and female between the ages of 12 and 18 at a public "reaping".
这些贡者斗士被送到国会大厦监管
These Tributes shall be delivered to the custody of the Capitol.
然后送到角斗场 他们将在那里战斗至死
And then transferred to a public arena where they will Fight to the Death,
直到剩下最后一个胜利者
until a lone victor remains.
从今往后 直到永远 这个盛会都会被称为饥饿游戏
Henceforth and forevermore this pageant shall be known as The Hunger Games.
我想 这是我们的传统…
I think its our tradition...
它来自于…
It comes out of a...
我们历史上特别痛苦的那一部分
particularly painful part of our history.
是 是
Yes. Yes.
但它已经变成我们能够治愈这个痛苦的方式
But it's been a way we've been able to heal.
起初 它只是叛乱的一个幸存者
At first it was a remainder of the rebellion
它是这个区必须付出的代价
It was the price the Districts had to pay.
但我认为它会由此成熟起来
But I think it has grown from that.
我觉得它是一个…
I think its a...
它把我们联系在一起
Its something that nets us all together.
这是你的第三个年头的比赛吗？
This is your third year's game?
您的个人签名是什么？
What defines your personal signature?
嘘 没关系
Shhhh. It's okay.
没关系 你只是在做梦
It's okay. You're just dreaming.
你正在做梦
You're dreaming.
我知道
I know.
我知道它像什么
I know what its like.
这是你的第一次招募 普里姆
It's your first, Prim,
你的名字只在他们那里出现一次 他们是不会选中你的
your name's gonna be there once, they're not gonna pick you!
睡吧
Try to go to sleep.
我不能
I can't.
试试吧
Just try.
在草地深处
Deep in the meadow.
在柳树下
Under the willow.
在草丛中单脚跳
Hop in the grass.
一个柔软的绿枕头
A soft green pillow.
你还记得那首歌吗？
You remember that song?
好吗
Ok.
你把它唱完
You finish it.
我得走了
I gotta go.
在哪里？
Where?
我就要走了
I just gotta go.
但我会回来的
But I'll be back.
我爱你
I love you.
我还是要把你烹了
I'll still cook you.
你杀了它后会怎么办
What're you gonna do with that when you kill it?
你这该死的 盖尔
Damn you, Gale!
这不好笑
It's not funny.
你对一头重达100磅的鹿能怎么办 凯特尼斯 ？
What're you gonna do with a 100 pound deer, Katnip?
这是招募日 到处都充斥着维和保安
It's Reaping Day, the place is crawling with Peacekeepers.
我本来要卖掉它
I was gonna sell it.
从维和保安…
from Peacekeepers...
当然你是
Of course you were.
卖给你 不卖给维和保安
Like you don't sell the Peacekeepers.
不 不是今天
No! Not today.
这是我一年里看到的第一个鹿
It's the first deer I've seen in a year.
现在 我什么都没有
Now, I have nothing.
好吧
Okay.
他们做了又能怎么样？只有你一个 为什么人们不停止观看呢？
What if they did? Just one you. Why if everyone just stop watching?
他们不会的 盖尔
They won't, Gale.
如果他们做了能怎么样？如果我们做了呢？
What if they did? What if we did?
不会发生
Won't happen.
你给你喜欢的选手加油 他们被杀掉 你就哭 太脆弱了
You root for your favorite, you cry when they get killed. It's sick.
盖尔
Gale.
如果没有人看…
If no one watches...
那么他们就没有这个游戏了 就是这么简单
Then they don't have a game. It's as simple as that.
什么？
What?
没什么
Nothing.
好的 笑…
Fine, laught at...
我没有笑你
I'm not laughing at you.
我们能做到这一点 你知道吗？
We could do it, you know?
离开 住在树林里 我们做什么呢？
Take off. Live in the woods. What we do anyway?
他们会抓住我们
They'd catch us.
也许不会
Maybe not.
切掉我们的舌头或者更糟
Cut out our tongues or worse.
我们不会跑出五英里的
We wouldn't make it five miles.
不 我已经走到5英里了
No, I get five miles.
我们会走那条路
We'll go that way.
我有普里姆 你有你的弟弟
I have Prim. You have your brothers.
他们也可以来
They can come too.
普里姆在树林里？
Prim in the woods?
也许不会
Maybe not.
我将不会有小孩
I'm never having kids.
没有可能
Not might.
如果我不住在这里
If I don't live here.
但是 你就是住在这里
But you do live here.
我知道 但如果我没有
I know, but if I didn't.
哦 我忘了
Oh, I forgot.
在这里
Here.
天啊
Oh my God!
这是真的吗？
Is this real?
是啊 最好是
Yeah. Better be.
我用一只松鼠买的
Cost me a squirrel.
饥饿游戏快乐
Happy Hunger Games.
希望好运永远属于你
And be the odds be ever in your favor.
你的名字到今天用了多少次？
How many times did your name in today?
42次？
Forty-two?
我想我不会那么好运正好被选中
I guess the odds aren't exactly in my favor.
谢谢你 女孩
Thank you girl.
这是什么？
What's this?
这是一个…学舌鸟
That's a...Mocking Jay
多少钱？
How much?
你拿着吧
You keep it.
它是你的
It's yours.
谢谢
Thank you.
妈妈？
Mom?
看看你
Aww. Look at you.
你看起来真漂亮
You look beautiful.
我们最好把那个小尾巴掖在后面
Let's better tuck in that tail by the back.
给你们两个做点什么吧
Made something out for you two.
好吧
Okay.
你看起来也很美
How you look beautiful too.
我们应该选你
We should ought pick you.
哦 不
Oh no.
这里是后面他们怎么选中你
Here's how it will pick you in the back.
屏住呼吸
Breathe.
想看看今天我给你带了什么？
Wanna see what I got you today?
它是学舌鸟胸针
It's a Mocking Jay pin.
能保护你
To protect you.
只要你拥有它
And as long as you have it.
坏事就不会在你身上发生
Nothing bad will happen to you.
好吗？
Okay?
我发誓
I promise.
嘘
Shh.
嘘 普里姆 没关系 没关系 嘘
Shh. Prim, it's okay. It's okay. Shh.
好吧 现在可以送她走了
Okay, it's time to send her now.
好吧 他们将刺破你的手指 只需要一点点血
Okay, they will prick your finger to take just a little bit of blood.
我很害怕
I'm scared.
普里姆 它不会有多大伤害的 只是一点点
Prim, it doesn't hurt much. Just a little.
好吗？
Okay?
去那里和小孩子坐在一起 我一会儿会来找你 好吗？
Go sit down there with the little kids. I'll find you after okay?
下一个
Next.
往前走
Go ahead.
下一个
Next.
欢迎
Welcome.
欢迎 欢迎
Welcome. Welcome.
快乐的饥饿游戏
Happy Hunger Games.
和…
And...
希望好运永远属于你
May the odds be ever in your favor.
现在 我们才开始
Now, before we begin.
我们有一个非常特别的电影
We have a very special film.
从国会大厦远道带过来的
Brought to you all the way from the Capitol.
战争
War.
可怕的战争
Terrible war.
这些…
With those...
孤儿和没有母亲的孩子
Orphan...and motherless child.
这就是带来了我们国土的暴动
This was the uprising that brought our land.
第13区背叛了哺育了他们的国家
13 Districts rebel against the country that fed them.
背叛了那个爱护着他们的国家
loved them, Protected them.
随后和平来了
Then came the peace.
猛烈的战斗
Hard fought.
完全胜利了
Solely won.
人民
The people.
从白骨中起义 然后一个新的时代诞生了
Rose up from the ashes and a new era was born.
自由是有代价的
The freedom has a cost.
叛徒被击败了
And the traitors was defeated.
作为一个国家的和平战争
Peace-War as a nation.
我们永远不再知道这个叛逆
We would never know this treason again.
同样 它已被制成法令…
And so, it was decreed...
每一年
That each year.
帕纳姆国的每个区将分别进献贡者斗士
The various districts of Panem would offer up in tribute...
一个年轻的男人和女人
One young man and woman.
他们将战斗到死
To fight to the death.
他们会被冠以荣誉 勇气和牺牲
And it peg you to honor, courage and sacrifice.
而那个孤独的胜利者…
The lone victor...
沐浴在财富中…
Bathe in riches...
将作为我们的慷慨
Will serve as our reminder of our generosity.
和我们的宽恕的鉴证
and our forgiveness.
我们这样记住过去
This is how we remember our past.
我们这样保证未来平安
This is how we safe guard our future.
我很喜欢那个
I just love that.
现在 是时候…
Now, the time has come to...
选择…
select...
一个勇敢的年轻的男人和女人
one courageous young man and woman.
会很荣幸的代表第12区参加第74届的饥饿游戏
For the honor of representing District 12 in the 74th Annual Hunger Games.
像往常一样…
As usual...
女士优先
ladies first.
普里姆 罗斯 伊夫狄恩
Primrose Everdeen!
你在哪里？
Where are you?
上来吧
Come on up.
好了 上来吧
Well, come on up!
普里姆
Prim!
我自愿作为贡者斗士
I volunteer as Tribute.
我相信我们有一个志愿者
I believe we have a volunteer.
你要离开这里
You need to get out of here.
没有
No!!
不
Noo!!
不 不
Noo! Nooo!!! Noooo!!
第12区发生了疯狂的转变
In mad of turn of events here on District 12.
这真是第12区的第一个志愿者 太惊讶了
District 12's very first volunteer. Big breath.
来吧亲爱的
Come on dear.
你叫什么名字？
What's your name?
凯特尼斯 伊夫狄恩
Katniss Everdeen.
好吧 我赌上我的帽子 这一定是你的妹妹
Well, I bet my hat that was your sister.
是不是？
Wasn't it?
是
Yes.
让我们为我们的第一个志愿者 凯特尼斯伊夫狄恩 猛烈鼓掌吧
Let's have a big hand for our very first volunteer, Katniss Everdeen.
现在…
And now...
选男孩
for the boys.
皮塔 迈拉克
Peeta Mellark.
我们来啦
Here we are.
我们12区的贡者斗士
Our Tributes from District 12.
嗯 你们两个去 握手
Well, go on you two. Shake hands.
饥饿游戏愉快
Happy Hunger Games.
幸运总在你这边
And be the odds be ever in your favor.
你有3分钟
You have 3 minutes.
普里姆 普里姆 没关系的
Prim, Prim, its okay.
嘘 普里姆 我没有太多的时间
Shh. Prim, I don't have much time.
普里姆 听着
Prim, listen.
你没事吧
You're gonna be okay.
不要拿任何额外的食物换钱
Don't take any extra food for money.
那并不值得把你的名字多次记录 好吗？
That doesn't worth putting your name in more times, okay?
听着 普里姆
Listen, Prim.
盖尔将带你玩游戏 他会在你的外衣里塞上奶酪
Gale will bring you game. He stuck cheese from your coat.
努力获胜 也许你能行
Just try to win. Maybe you can.
也许我能行 我很聪明 你知道的
Maybe I can, I am smart you know?
你会打猎
You can hunt.
没错
Exactly.
这个可以保护你
It's to protect you.
谢谢
Thank you.
你不要再让她的名字入围了
You can't turn out again.
我不会了
I won't
不 你不能
No, you can't.
这和父亲去世时的情形不一样
Not like when dad died.
我不会在这里了 你就是她的一切了
I won't be here anymore. Your all she has.
不管你的感觉如何 你到那里就是为了她的 你明白吗？
No matter what you feel, you will be there for her. You understand?
不要哭了
Don't cry.
不要哭了 不要
Don't cry. Don't.
不 不
No! No!
我发誓 普里姆
I promise Prim.
我没事
I'm fine.
你不知道
You don't know.
我是
I am.
听我说
Listen to me.
你比他们强 你是
You're stronger than they are. You are.
拿一张弓 你就可以告诉他们你有多好
Get to a bow. What will if you show them how good you are?
他们只是想要一个漂亮的演出 这就是他们想要的一切
They just want a good show. That's all they want.
如果他们没有弓 那么你就做一个 好吗？你知道如何打猎
If they don't have a bow, then you make one. Okay? You know how to hunt.
他们不是动物
They're not animals.
这没有什么不同 凯特尼斯
It's no different Katniss.
盖尔 那里有24个人 只有一个能出来
There's 24 of us Gale and only one comes out.
是啊
Yeah.
那一定会是你
And it's gonna be you.
好吧
Okay.
照顾他们 盖尔 不管你做什么 不要让他们挨饿
Take care of them Gale. Whatever you do, don't let them starve.
走吧
Let's go!
我很快就会来看你 好吗？
I'll see you soon okay?
你们两个还没有去过那里吧？
You two haven't had trip?
水晶吊灯
Crystal chandeliers.
铂金色甜甜圈
Platinum donuts.
每小时200英里 你几乎感觉不到什么
200 miles per hour and you can barely feel a thing.
我觉得这个机会是一件美妙的事情…
I think its rather a wonderful thing is about this opportunity...
即使你在这里 即使它只是一小会儿
That even though you're here and even though it's just for a little while.
你可以享受这一切
You get to enjoy all of this.
我要去找到海米奇
I'm going to find Haymitch.
他很可能在后面的车厢
He's probably in the back car.
你见过他吗？
You even met him?
海米奇？
Haymitch?
凯特尼斯 你知道 他是我们的导师
You know, Katniss, he is our mentor.
他做过一次目击证人
He did witness things once.
瞧
Look!
你知道 如果你不想说话 我明白
You know if you don't want to talk, I understand.
但我不认为想得到一点帮助有什么错误
But I just don't think there's anything wrong of getting a little bit of help.
祝贺
Congratulations.
冰在哪里？
Where's the ice?
我不知道…我不知道
I don't...I don't know.
好吧 呃…
Okay, so uh...
所以 我们什么时候开始？
so when do we start?
哦
Whoah.
为什么这么渴望呢？
Why so eager?
你们中的大多数是这样匆忙
Most of you are in such a hurry.
是啊 我想知道计划是什么 你是我们的导师 你应该去…
Yeah. I wanna know what the plan is. You're our mentor, you're supposed to go...
再来一遍
Encore.
是啊
Yeah.
我们的导师应该告诉我们如何得到赞助 并给我们建议
Our mentor is supposed to tell us how to get sponsors and give us advice.
哦 好吧
Oh, okay.
恩
Ummm...
发现可能致死的潜在因素
Embrace the probability of your immanent death.
我知道
I know.
你的心脏能…
Can your heart...
我做什么也救不了你
that there's nothing I can do to save you.
那么 为什么你在这里呢？
So why are you here then?
茶点
The refreshments.
好吧 我想这就足够了
Okay, I think that's enough.
你把我的饮料
You made me spill my drink.
洒到我的新裤子上了
over my new pants.
你知道吗…
You know...
我本想我会在我房间里去完成这些事情
I think I'll go finish this in my room.
我不应该过来
I shouldn't have come around.
什么？这是没有用的
What? It's no use.
我要去和他谈谈
I'm gonna go talk to him.
我们有两个 16岁的
We have two, 16 year olds.
是
Yes.
你还记得这一年的？
Do you remember this year?
哦 是我最喜欢一年
Aww. One of my favorite years.
我最喜爱的角斗之一
And one of my favorite arenas.
利用碎石以及城市的废墟
The use of the rubble, the ruin city.
非常令人兴奋
Very exciting.
在这里 此时…
From this moment here...
此刻…
this moment...
是你永远不会忘记的那一刻…
is the moment that you never forget.
那一刻…
The moment...
当一个贡品斗士…
when a Tribute...
成为胜利者
becomes a victor.
首先你会冻死
You'd freeze to death first.
因为我没有生火
Because I didn't light a fire.
那样被杀死也挺不错的
Now that's a good way to get killed.
有什么好的办法被整死吗？
What's a good way to get killed?
哦 乔伊
Oh! Joy.
你为什么不加入我们呢？
Why don't you join us?
我只是说了能救命的建议
I'm just gaving a life-saving advice.
像什么呢？
Like what?
我…我只是问如何寻找避难所
I wa...I was just asking about how to find shelter.
如果事实上你仍然活着 这将派上用场
Which would come in handy if in fact you are still alive.
你如何找到避难所？
How do you find shelter?
把果酱给我
Pass the jam.
你如何找到避难所？
How do you find shelter?
给我一个机会 醒醒吧 亲爱的
Give me a chance to wake up sweetheart.
这个指导是非常…
This mentoring is very...
浪费税收和材料
tax and stuff.
能把桔子酱递给我吗？
Can you pass the marmalade?
这是红木的
That is mahogany.
你看你
Look at you!
刚刚杀掉了一块餐桌上的垫布
Just killed a...place mat!
你真的想知道如何生存？
You really wanna know how to stay alive?
你要让别人喜欢你
You get people to like you.
哦
Oh!
不是你期待的那些东西
Not what you're expecting.
当你在游戏中…
When you're in the middle of the games...
你在挨饿或挨冻
and you're starving or freezing,
一点水
some water,
一把刀 甚至几根火柴都可能决定生死
a knife or even some matches can mean the difference between life and death.
这些东西只能从赞助商那里获得
And those things only comes from Sponsors.
而要获得赞助商支持 你必须让人喜欢你
And to get Sponsors, you have to make people like you.
而现在 亲爱的？
And right now, sweetheart?
你离一个好开端并不远
You're not off to a really good start.
它就在那里
There it is.
它很大呀
It's huge.
那真是难以置信
That's incredible.
来吧
Come on.
最好带着这把刀
Better keep this knife.
他知道他在做什么
He knows what he's doing.
所以 现在您已经看到了…
So now that you've seen...
你觉得这几年科若佛部队怎么样？
what do you think of this years cropful troops?
今年会给我们带来什么惊喜吗？
Are there any surprises that we can expect this year?
这真的很难从目前的招募中看出结果 但我觉得…
It's really hard to tell from a Reaping but I think...
这是一个非常有趣的一群人
this is a very interesting mix.
有些东西是你不能忽略的
it's something you can't ignore.
那是什么？
What's that?
我们只是说我们可能需要把你放倒用水管再冲一遍,
We were just saying we might need to hose you down again
在我们带你见辛纳之前
before we take you to Cinna.
这是我见过的最勇敢的事情
That was all the bravest thing I've ever seen.
我是辛纳
I am Cinna.
凯特尼斯
Katniss.
很对不起 这事发生在你身上
I'm sorry that this happened to you.
我在这里可以帮助你
And I'm here to help you in any way I can.
大多数人都祝贺我
Most people just congratulate me.
我看不到有什么值得祝贺的
I don't see the point in that.
所以 今晚…
So tonight...
他们会举行贡者斗士游行
they have the Tribute Parade.
让我带你出去和然后展示给你
Let me take you out and show you after the wurl.
所以 你在这里让我看起来漂亮点
So you're here to make me look pretty.
我来这里是为了帮助你给别人留下深刻印象
I'm here to help you make an impression.
通常 他们按照接近他们的区的服装打扮那些人
Now usually, they dress people in their close to their district.
是啊 我们被叫做未成年人
Yeah. We're called minors.
是啊 但我并不想这样做
Yeah. But I don't want to do that.
我要做一些会让他们记得住的东西
I'm gonna do something that they're gonna remember.
他们解释了关于争取获得赞助商帮助了吗？
Did they explain about trying to get sponsors?
是啊 但我并不是很善于交朋友
Yeah, but I'm not very good at making friends.
让我们拭目以待
We'll see.
我只是觉得 人的勇敢…
I just think, somebody that brave...
不应该被穿上一些愚蠢的服装
shouldn't be dressed up on some stupid costume as should they.
我希望不会
I hope not.
这不是真正的火 这些套装搞成这样你就不会感觉到单调
It's not real fire. These suits are built so you won't feel a thing.
这对我更好
That's better on me.
这个想法…
The idea...
你准备好了吗？
You ready?
不要害怕
Don't be afraid.
我不害怕
I'm not afraid.
超过十万人 张望着 为了看一眼今年的贡者斗士…
Over one hundred thousand people, craning to get a glimpse this year's Tributes...
赞助商也是第一次见到这些贡者斗士们
and the Sponsors get to see the Tributes for the first time.
这一时刻的重要性是无需夸大的
The importance of this moment cannot be over stated.
他们很好
They're nice.
首先跟着我的倒计时欢呼吧 15…
First cheered on my counting in 15...
14… 13…
14 ... 13 ...
他们在这里 他们在这里
Here they are. Here they are.
今年的贡者斗士
This year's Tributes.
最激动人心的时候到了
The most exciting run...
它只会让你起鸡皮疙瘩
it just gives you goose bumps.
难道你不爱 造型师是怎么搞的…
Don't you love, how the stylist...
他们能够在造型上如此明显的反映出每个地区的特点
they so clearly are able to reflect the character of each district.
有4区
There's District 4!
这是非常好的
That's very good.
而在他们身后…
And behind them...
我们有两个电厂工人
we have two power plant workers.
然后…
And then...
在背景那里是什么东西？
what is that in the background?
来吧 他们一定会喜欢这样的
Come on. They'll love it.
现在看到了吗？我喜欢这个
Now see that? I love that.
两个年轻人 一起举着他们的手
Two young people, holding their hands up!
他说:  "我很自豪 我从12区来 我们将不容忽视 "
Saying, "I'm proud, I'm from District 12! We will not be overlooked!"
我喜欢这个
I love that.
我们确定我们将马上关注他们
We're gonna sure we'll be paying attention to them right now!
我们准备好了
and we're ready.
斯诺总统 你开始直播
President Snow, you're live!
欢迎
Welcome.
贡者斗士们
Tributes.
我们欢迎你
We welcome you.
我们赞赏…
We salute...
你们的勇气…
the courage...
你们的牺牲精神
and your sacrifice.
我们祝你…
And we wish you...
饥饿游戏中愉快
happy Hunger Games.
幸运永远属于你
And may the odds be ever in your favor.
那是惊人的
That was amazing.
哦 我们将是任何人都在谈论的对象
Oh, we are anybody's going be talking about.
如此勇敢
So brave.
你确定你制造了一个新的火焰吗？
Are you sure you're spinning up a new flame?
假的火焰？
Fake flame?
你确定吗？
Are you sure?
这是恩…
That's uh...
让我们去楼上
let's go upstairs.
因此每个地区对应自己的楼层
So each of the districts got their own floor
因为你从12区来 所以你在顶层阁楼
and because you're from 12, you get the penthouse.
来吧
Come on.
因此 这是客厅
So this is the living room.
我知道了
I know!
现在 你的房间就在这里
Now, your rooms are right over here.
你为什么不在晚餐前把自己简单收拾一下
Why don't you go clean yourselves up a little before dinner.
在两个星期内…
In two weeks...
你们中的23人会死掉
23 of you will be dead.
只有一个人会活着
One of you will be alive.
那个人是谁 取决于你们对未来四天如何关注
Who that is depends on how well you pay attention over the next four days.
尤其是对我将要说的
Particularly to what I'm about to say.
第一 不和其他贡者斗士打斗
First. No fighting with the other Tributes.
在角斗场上 你将有足够的时间来打
You'll have plenty of time for that in the arena.
有四个必选练习 剩下的是个体的训练
There are four compulsory exercises, the rest will be individual training.
我的建议是…
My advice is...
不要忽视生存技能
Don't ignore the survival skills.
每个人都想抓住剑 但你们中的大多数将死于自然原因
Everybody wants to grab a sword but most of you will die from natural causes.
10％ 死于传染病
10% from infection.
20％死于脱水
20% from dehydration.
暴露可以像一把刀那样容易的杀人
Exposure can kill as easily as a knife.
我的刀在哪里？
Where's my knife?
我把我的刀放到…
I put my knife...
不要碰我…
Don't touch me...
他妈的 你拿走了我的刀
Fuck! You took my knife!
我没有碰你的刀 我没碰你的…
I didn't touch your knife. I didn't touch your kni...
你这个骗子
You liar.
你这个小朋克
You little punk!
你拿了我的刀
You took my knife.
离我远点
Get off me.
坐在这里
Just sit here.
我会在角斗场等你的
I should better wait for the arena.
你将是我干掉的第一个人 所以你最好小心点 嗯
You're the first one I get so watch your back huh!
每个人都回到线上
Everybody back in line.
你知道我下一个对手就是你 卡托
You know you're next to me Cato!
忙碌的工作
Busy career.
你知道那是什么？
You know what that is?
从1区
From District 1.
到2区
and 2.
他们一直想在18岁前考上一个特殊的学院
They've been trying to be in a special academy
他们也愿意那样 到了那个时候…
till they're 18 and they volunteer. By that point...
他们是相当致命的
they're pretty lethal.
但他们不会受到任何特殊对待
But they don't receive any special treatment.
事实上 他们住在和你们完全相同的公寓里
In fact, they're staying at the exact same apartment as you do.
我不认为可以给他们留下甜点 但可以给你们
And I don't think left them out for dessert and you can.
那么 一切都还好？
So how good all that?
显然 他们是相当不错的 好多年他们都赢了 但…
Obviously, they're pretty good. They won in almost several year but...
几乎…
Almost...
他们就变得傲慢了
They can be arrogant.
而傲慢会是个大问题
And arrogance can be a big problem.
我听说你会射箭…
I hear you can shoot...
还可以吧
I'm alright.
其实 比还可以更好
Actually, better than alright.
我给她送过松鼠
I fed her by the squirrels.
他说 她打它们都是正好击中眼睛 每次都是
He say she hits them right in the eye, everytime.
皮塔非常强壮
Peeta's strong.
好吧 我不会用一袋面粉杀掉一个人
Okay, well I cannot kill anybody by a sack of flour.
不 当有人拿着刀子从你身后过来时
No, you might have a better chance
你就会有一个更好的机会获胜
at winning when somebody comes after you with a knife.
我没有获胜的机会 没有 好吗？
I have no chance of winning. None! Alright?
这是真的
It's true.
大家都知道它
Everybody knows it.
你知道我的母亲说什么吗？
You know what my mother said?
她说 "12区终于会有一个赢家 "
She said, "District 12 might finally have a winner!"
但她不是在说我
But she wasn't talking about me.
她是在说你
She was talking about you.
我不是非常饿
I'm not very hungry.
我也吃完了
I'm done too.
把那个金属物扔过去
Throw that metal thing over there.
什么？
What?
不
No.
海米奇说 他们不希望我们表演…
Haymitch says we're not supposed to show...
我才不在乎海米奇说过什么
I don't care what Haymitch said.
那些家伙都看着你 就像你是一顿饭一样
Those guys are looking at you like you're a meal.
扔掉它
Throw it.
您好
Hi.
嘿
Hey.
你是怎么做的呢？
How did you do that?
我 呃…
I uh...
我曾经在面包店干过
I used to take care of the cakes down at the bakery.
我会展示给你看
I'll show you.
看到了？
See?
哇
Wow.
是啊
Yeah.
我觉得有人跟着你
I think you have a shadow.
明天 他们将带你进去 一个一个的
Tomorrow. They will bring you in one by one.
对你进行评估
And evaluate you.
这是重要的 因为高收视率将意味着获得赞助商赞助
This is important because high ratings will mean Sponsors.
是给他们展示一切的时候了
This is the time to show them everything.
那将会有一张弓 确保你会用上它
There'll be a bow, make sure you use it.
皮塔 你一定要展现出你的力量
Peeta, you make sure to show your strength.
他们先从1区开始 所以你们两个将在最后出现
They'll start with District 1 so the two of you will go last.
不要在我的房间戴上这个…
Not on my house to put this...
确保让他们记得你
Make sure they remember you!
凯特尼斯 伊夫狄恩
Katniss Everdeen.
嘿 凯特尼斯
Hey Katniss.
直接射击
Shoot straight.
凯特尼斯 伊夫狄恩
Katniss Everdeen.
12区
District 12.
谢谢
Thank you.
请你们考虑
For your consideration.
你疯了吗？
Are you crazy?
我只是生气
I just got mad.
疯了吗？
Mad?!
你意识到你的行动给我们所有人招致严重后果
You realize that your actions reflect badly on all of us.
不只是你
Not just you.
他们只是想要一个精彩的表演 这很正常
They just want a good show, it's fine.
没有礼貌会怎么样？辛纳
How about just bad manners Cinna?
会怎么样？
How about that?
好吧 最后
Well, finally!
我希望你注意到 我们的形势非常严峻
I hope you notice, we have a serious situation.
很漂亮的射箭表演 甜心
Nice shooting sweetheart!
他们…他们在干什么 当你射中那个苹果的时候？
Wha...Wha...What did they...What did they do when you shot the apple?
恩 他们看起来很吃惊
Well, they look pretty startled.
你说什么… 谢谢…
What did you say...Thanks for...
考虑 天才
consideration. Genius!
天才
Genius.
你怎么想的 你觉得这个很有趣吗？
How do you think you're gonna find this funny?
如果游戏制造者决定让它出局…
if the game makers decided to take it out...
谁？让她？
On who? On her?
让他？
On him?
我认为他们已经有了
I think they already have.
松开你的紧身胸衣 然后喝一杯吧
Loosen your corset and have a drink.
我会不惜一切代价看到结果的
I would have given anything to see it.
正如你所知道的 这些贡者斗士将被仔细评估
As you know the Tributes are rated on a scale of 1 to 12
3天后将从1到12被排名分级
after three days of careful evaluation.
游戏管理员会这样评估…
The game keepers would like to evaluate...
从1区 马布尔
From District 1, Marvel.
从7区…
From District 7...
9分
The score of 9.
卡托 10分
Cato, the score of 10.
克劳夫 10分
Clove, the score of 10.
四 得分…
Four, score of ...
从区…
From District...
芸香 7分
Rue, the score of 7.
从12区…
From District 12...
皮塔 迈拉克…
Peeta Mellark...
得分…
The score of...
8.
不错 布拉沃
Not bad. Bravo.
最后…
And finally...
从区12…
From District 12...
凯特尼斯 伊芙迪恩…
Katniss Everdeen...
得分是…
With the score of...
十一分
eleven.
祝贺
Congratulations.
我认为 他们恨我
I thought they hated me.
他们必须有像你这样的女孩
They must have like you girl.
祝贺 凯特尼斯 伊芙迪恩…
To Katniss Everdeen...
燃烧的女孩
The Girl On Fire!
在第十一？
At eleven?
她赢得了它
She earned it.
她在你的头上射了一箭
She shot an arrow at your head.
好吧 只是一个苹果
Well, t'was an apple.
在你的头附近
near your head.
坐下
Sit down.
塞涅卡…
Seneca...
为什么你认为我们有一个赢家？
why do you think we have a winner?
你是什么意思？
What do you mean?
我的意思是…
I mean...
为什么我们有一个胜利者？
why do we have a winner?
我的意思是 如果我们只是想恐吓各个区
I mean if we just wanted to intimidate the Districts,
为什么不把这24个人随机组合立刻比赛 这个方法快了很多…
why not round up 24 of them at random and execute them all at once. Way a lot faster...
希望
Hope.
希望吗？
Hope?
希望
Hope.
它是唯一比恐惧更强烈的事情
It is the only thing...stronger than fear.
一点点的希望是有效的
A little hope is effective.
一个很大的希望是危险的
A lot of hope is dangerous.
它的轨迹是不错的…只要它是可控制的
It's track is fine...as long as it's contained.
所以…
So...
所以…控制它
So...contain it!
好的
Right.
如果她正在盯着我的珠宝首饰 她不会把她的眼睛从…
If she's staring at all my jewels, she can't take her eye from...
坦率地说…这很粗鲁
Frankly...it was rude.
哦 海米奇 你应该和我们一起 我们有一些你最爱吃的菜
Oh, Haymitch. You should join us. We're having some of your favorite dish.
哦 可爱的
Oh, lovely.
哪里皮塔？
Where's Peeta?
他在自己的房间 现在听着…
He's in his room. Now listen...
明天是最后一天
Tomorrow's the last day.
他们要求我们在比赛开始前和自己的贡者斗士一起走
When they let us walk with our own Tributes right before the game
你和我将在9点下楼
so you and I will be going down at 9.
那么 他怎么办？
Well, what about him?
没有 他说 他希望从现在开始要对自己训练
No, he says he wants to be trained on his own from now on.
什么？
What?
这种事情只有在这个时候发生 那就是…
This kind of thing does happen at this point if there's...
只有一个赢家 对不对？
only one winner. Right?
我们应该有一些巧克力覆盖斯托克
We should have some chocolate covered stoke.
女士们 先生们 您的司仪…
Ladies and gentlemen. Your master of ceremonies...
凯撒闪光人
Caesar Flickerman!
谢谢
Thank you!
欢迎 欢迎 欢迎 欢迎
Welcome, welcome, welcome, welcome.
来到第74届饥饿游戏
To the 74th Annual Hunger Games.
现在 还有五分钟 他们就都出来了
Now, there are five minutes they are all going to be out here.
所有你听说过的贡者斗士
All of the Tributes that you heard about.
你高兴吗？
Are you excited?
让我听吧
Let me hear it!
惊人的
Amazing.
我不觉得惊人
I don't feel amazing.
难道你不知道你是多么美丽？
Don't you know how beautiful you look?
我不知道如何让别人喜欢我 你是怎么让别人来喜欢你的呢？
No. And I don't know how to make people like me, how do you make people like you?
你为什么让我喜欢你？
Why do you made me like you?
这是不同的 我并不想
That's different. I wasn't trying.
没错
Exactly.
只要做回你自己 整个过程我都会在那里的
Just be yourself. I'll be there the whole time.
假装你跟我说话
and just pretend you're talking to me.
好吗？
Okay?
好吧
Okay.
让我们来看看她是否真的闪亮光芒
Let's see if she does indeed shine.
让我们用热烈的掌声送给格力马
Let's have a warm round of applause for Glimmer.
格力马 你准备好了吗？
Glimmer, are you prepared?
是凯撒 我准备好了
Yes Caesar, I am prepared.
我喜欢它 那只是…
I like it, that's just...
一大圈的掌声
Big round of applause.
马布尔
Marvel!
欢迎克劳夫
Welcome Clove.
这是一种荣誉 能代表我的区出场
It's an honor to represent my district.
所以你是一个战士？
so you're a fighter?
我准备好了对付恶毒的东西 我要去了
I'm prepared, vicious and I'm ready to go.
卡托
Cato!
从12区来的…
From District 12...
你知道她的…
You know her...
作为燃烧的女孩
as the girl on fire!
她就是凯特尼斯 伊芙迪恩
Where we know it's Katniss Everdeen!
什么？
What?
我觉得某个人显得有点紧张
I think someone's a little nervous.
前几天 在贡者斗士游行的入口 我说过同样的话
I said that was quite and entrance that you've made at the Tribute's Parade the other day.
你要告诉我们吗？
Do you want to tell us about it?
好吧 我只是…
Well, I was just...
希望我不会把它烧了
hoping that I wouldn't burned it up!
当你从那个战车上下来…
When you came out of that chariot...
我不得不说…
I have to say...
我的心…停了下来
My heart...stopped.
也为了获得你的经验值
To earn you experiences as well.
我的心脏停止跳动
My heart stopped.
我的心也停了
So did mine.
我现在告诉我关于火焰…他们是真的吗？
Now tell me about the flames...are they real?
是
Yes.
事实上 我今天正好穿着它们
In fact I'm wearing them today.
你想看看吗？
Would you like to see?
等待 等待 等待
Wait, wait, wait.
安全吗？
Is it safe?
你认为大伙是怎么想的呢？
What do you think folks?
我认为拿就是一个"是"
I think that's a yes!
这是真正的东西
That was really something.
凯特尼斯 很有意思
Katniss, that was something.
向你表示感谢
Thank you for that.
我有一个问题问你
I have one more question for you.
是关于你妹妹的…
It's about your sister...
我们都非常感动 我觉得…
We are all very moved, I think when...
当你志愿代替她当贡者斗士的时候
you volunteered for her at the Reaping.
她过来向你道别了吗
Does she come to say goodbye to you.
是
Yes.
她做到了
She did.
你对他说了什么？
And what did you say to her?
在最后？
In the end?
我告诉她 我会尽力取胜
I told her that I would try to win.
我将尽力为她取胜
That I will try to win for her.
当然你做了
Of course you did.
你也将去努力
And try you will.
女士们 先生们 来自12区的
Ladies and gentlemen, from District 12,
凯特尼斯·伊芙迪恩 燃烧的女孩
Katniss Everdeen, The Girl On Fire!!
你做到了 亲爱的
You did it darling.
这是不可思议的
That was incredible.
谢谢
Thank you.
干的好 甜心
Nice job sweetheart.
谢谢
Thank you.
服装也好
Nice dress too.
是你的吗？
Are yours?
皮塔 迈拉克
Peeta Mellark!
皮塔 欢迎
Peeta, welcome.
你是怎么找到国会的？不要说是看地图找到的
How are you finding the Capitol? Don't say with a map.
呃 那是不同的
Uh, it's uh...different.
这是非常不同的
It's very different.
有什么不同？是在哪？给我们一个例子
Different? In what are? Give us an example.
嗯 好吧 这里的淋浴室非常古怪
Uh okay, well the showers here are weird.
淋浴室？
Showers?
是
Yes.
我们有不同的淋浴室
We have different showers.
我有一个问题问你 凯撒
I have a question for you Caesar.
你觉得我闻起来像玫瑰吗？
Do I smell like roses to you?
嗯…
Um...
像吗？
Do I?
是啊
Yeah.
我闻起来像吗？
Do I smell like it?
你一定闻起来比我的更好
You definitely smell better than I do.
我住在这里的时间比你长
Well I live here longer.
所以皮塔…
So Peeta...
告诉我
tell me.
有没有一个特殊的女孩回家？
Is there a special girl back home?
没有 真的没有
No, not really.
没有？我一刻也不相信他
No? I don't believe it for a second.
看看那张脸 像你这样英俊的男人…皮塔
Look at that face. Handsome man like you...Peeta.
告诉我
Tell me.
嗯 有1…
Well, there a...
有一个女孩…
There's this one girl that...
我一直迷恋着
I had a crush on forever.
但我不认为她真的认识我 直到招募的时候
But I don't think she actually recognize me until the Reaping.
嗯…
Well...
我会告诉你什么 皮塔
I'll tell you what Peeta.
你出去到那里…
You go out there...
你会赢了这个游戏
and you win this thing.
当你回家时
And when you get home.
她会和你一起出去
She'll have to go out with you.
是不是呀 观众们？
Right folks?
谢谢…但我 我不认为胜利会帮助我
Thanks but I uh...I don't think winnings gonna help me at all.
为什么不会呢？
And why not
因为她跟我一起来到这里
Because she came here with me.
嗯 这的确不幸
Well, that's bad luck.
是啊 这是
Yeah. It is.
我祝愿所有好运都属于你
And I wish you all the best of luck.
谢谢
Thank you.
皮塔 迈拉克
Peeta Mellark.
12区
District 12!
到底是什么呢？
What the hell is that?!
你不跟我说话 你说你对我有好感吗？
You don't talk to me and you say you have a crush on me?
你说你想单独训练 那就是你想怎么玩吗？
You say you wanna train alone...is that how you wanna play?
住手 住手
Stop! Stop it!
马上开始吧
Start right now.
他帮了你的忙
He did you a favor.
他让我看起来很虚弱
He made me look weak.
他让你看起来富有魅力
He made you look desirable.
像你这种情况 不能伤害 甜心
Which in your case, can't hurt sweetheart!
他是对的 凯特尼斯
He's right Katniss.
当然 我是对的
Of course, I'm right.
现在 我可以出售12区的牛郎织女了
Now I can sell the star cross lovers from District 12.
我们不是牛郎织女
We are not star cross lovers.
这是一个电视节目
It's a television show.
而且爱上了那个男孩能让你拉来赞助商 这可以救你那该死的命
And being in love with that boy might just get you Sponsors which could save your damn life.
好吧…为什么你不离开这里呢？
Okay...why don't you get out of here?
也许明天的直播表演能救你们俩呢
Maybe acting to live save you both to one piece tomorrow.
礼貌
Manners.
你也在？
You too?
哦 嘿嘿
Oh, hey.
无法入睡？
Can't sleep?
不 当然不是
No, of course not.
对不起 我跟着你
I'm sorry I went after you.
你知道我的意思是在恭维你
You know I meant that as a compliment.
我知道
I know.
听…
Listen...
耶？
Yeah?
我只是不想改变自己
I just don't wanna change me.
他们是如何改变你的？
How did they change you?
我不知道
I don't know.
我变得有点不像我了
I'm turning to something I'm not.
我只是不想在他们的比赛中变成另一个我 你知道吗？
I just don't wanna be another piece in their game, you know?
你的意思是你不会杀死任何人吗？
You mean you won't kill anyone?
不
No.
我还不确定我会的
I'm not yet sure I would.
就像我不知道是否还有时间继续
Just like any by off my time came with.
是啊 我只是想我能找到一个办法向他们表示:
Yeah, I just keep...wishing I could think of a way to show them.
他们并没有拥有我
That they don't own me.
你知道 如果我死了
You know, if I'm gonna die.
我还想是我
I wanna still be me.
有什么感觉吗？
Does that make any sense?
是啊
Yeah.
我只是不能像你那样去想
I just can't afford to think like that.
我想念我的妹妹
I miss my sister.
是的 我知道
Yeah I know.
想想 明天见
Guess, I'll see you tomorrow.
明天见
See you tomorrow.
他们把各种人放在前面
They put all kind of stuff right in front.
就在丰饶之角的嘴里
Right in the mouth of the Cornocopia.
甚至还会有一张弓
There'll even be a bow there.
不要去了
Don't go for it.
为什么不呢？
Why not?
这是大屠杀 他们试图让你进来 这不是你玩的
It's a Bloodbath, they're trying to pull you in. It's not your game.
轮到你了 跑吧 找到一个制高点
You turn, run, find a high ground.
寻找水 水是你新的最好的朋友
Look for water. Water's your new bestfriend.
不要太早离开台座 他们会把你吹上天的
Don't step off that pedestal earlier or they'll blow you sky high.
我不会
I won't.
凯特尼斯
Katniss.
你可以做到的
You can do this.
谢谢
Thanks.
给我你的手臂
Give me your arm.
那是什么？
What is that?
你的追踪器
Your tracker.
不到一分钟了 同志们
Less than a minute people!
最后检查
Final checks.
15秒后 它们就飞起来了
So fifteen up, they are flying.
在这里
Here.
谢谢
Thank you.
30秒
30 seconds.
他们不允许我赌
I'm not allowed to bet.
但如果我能赌 我赌你赢
But if i could I'd bet on you!
20秒
20 seconds.
10秒
10 seconds.
好的 他们到管子里面了
Okay, they're in the tubes.
50…
50...
49…
49...
48…
48...
47… 46…
47...46...
45… 44…
45...44...
43… 42…
43...42...
41… 40…
41...40...
39… 38…
39...38...
37… 36…
37...36...
35… 34…
35...34...
33… 32…
33...32...
31… 30…
31...30...
29… 28
29...28
27… 26…
27...26...
25… 24…
25...24...
23… 22…
23...22...
当然…
And of course...
听到了熟悉的大炮声
There's the familiar boom of the cannon.
这标志着又一个贡者斗士倒下了
Which marks the end of another fallen Tribute.
嗯 在前8个小时已经倒下13个了
Well, that maes 13 gone in the first eight hours.
克劳狄斯 我想我看到了一结盟正在组成
And Claudius, I think I seen alliance forming.
请不要杀我 噢 不
Please don't kill me. Oh no!
嘿 小白脸
Hey, loverboy!
你确定她是从这条路走的？
You sure she went this way?
是啊 我敢肯定
Yeah, I'm sure.
你最好
You better be.
是啊 那里有个梳子
Yeah. That was a steer comb back there.
你确定我们现在不应该杀死他吗？
Are you sure we shouldn't just kill him now?
通过他 我们很容易找到她
Nah. He's our best chance at finding her.
先生
Sir.
她几乎到边界了
She is almost at the edge.
距离最近的贡者斗士也有2公里远
Two kilometers away from the nearest Tribute.
转到她的周围看看
Let's turn her around.
用我的账户干掉另一个人…一个
Killing another on my account...one.
两个
Two.
嗯 她奔向左翼
Uh, she's heading towards the left flank.
好吧
Okay.
肯定
Sure.
她快到了
She's almost there.
露西亚 准备大炮
Lucia, get a cannon ready.
哦 她在那里 她在那里
Oh there she is. There she is.
你有什么 宝贝？
What you got baby?
杀掉她 卡托
Kill her Cato!
我来抓你了
I'm coming for you!
我自己就行
I'll do it myself.
抓住她
Get her!
来吧 来吧
Come on. Come on.
也许你应该用你的飞剑
Maybe you should throw the sword.
我们等她出来
Let's just wait her out.
他总会下来的 到那时再杀她
She's gonna come down at some points. That's gonne start her there.
好吧
Okay.
找人点火
Somebody make a fire.
谢谢
Thank you.
克劳迪斯 我认为那些是追踪黄蜂 我错了吗？
Claudius. I think those are trackerjackers. Am I wrong?
哦
ho...
这些东西都是非常致命的
Those things are very lethal.
非常
Very.
那些东西是你们不知道的
For those of you who don't know.
追踪黄蜂是转基因后的黄蜂
Trackerjackers are genetically engineered wasps.
其毒液会产生剧痛
Whose venom causes serious pain.
强大的幻觉甚至会导致死亡
Powerful hallucinations and in extreme cases, death.
快跑
Run!
该死 走
Damn it. Go!
凯特尼斯 没有 你在干什么？
Katniss, no! What're you doing?
去
Go!
叮咬即使不致命
Hallow isn't lethal.
但一只追踪黄蜂刺上的毒液…
But the venom of a trackerjacker sting...
是足以产生想睡觉的幻觉
is enough to doze off hallucinations.
请做一些事情
Please do something.
凯特尼斯 去
Katniss, go!
离开这里 你在干什么？去
Get out of here! What're you doing? Go!
芸香？
Rue?
没关系 我不会伤害你的
It's okay. I'm not gonna hurt you.
你想吃我的这个吗？
You want mine too?
不 不用
No, that's okay.
拿着吧
Here.
谢谢
Thanks.
多久 我睡着了吗？
How long was I asleep?
2天
A couple of days.
我给你换了两次树叶
I change your leaves twice.
谢谢
Thank you.
当我不在的时候 都发生了什么事？
So what happened? When I was out?
1区的女孩和10区的男孩
The girl from 1 and the boy from 10.
和…
And the uh...
和我这个区的男孩吗？
And the boy from my district?
没有 他没事
No, he's okay.
我认为他掉到河里面了
I think he's down by the river.
都是真实的吗？
Is all about true?
什么？
What?
你和他
You and him.
那么 卡托和其他人呢？
So where are Cato and the others?
他们在湖边得到了供给
They got all their supplies down by the lake.
都在这个大金字塔形堆里
It's prod up in this great big pyramid.
这听起来很诱人
That sounds tempting.
现在 这个绿色的东西会疯狂的冒烟
Now this green stuff is gonna smoke like crazy
所以你一点着它 就马上点下一个
so as soon as you light it. Move on to the next fire.
最后再点燃这个
Light this one last.
我会回到这和你会合
And I'll meet you back over here.
好的
Right.
当他们追我们时 我会毁掉他们的东西
I'll destroy their stuff while they're chasing us.
我们要个暗号 以防我们中的一个被抓走
We need a signal, in case one of us gets held up.
好吧 是什么呢？
Okay. Like what?
在这里 看这个
Here. Watch this.
学舌鸟
Mocking jays.
太好了
That's great.
在家里 我们就用它们当暗号
Back home, we used them to signal all the time...
你试试
You try.
好吧 如果我们听到那个 就意味着我们没事而且很快就会回来
Okay so, if we hear that means we're okay and we'll be back real soon.
我们会没事的
We're gonna be okay.
嘿
Hey.
我等你吃晚饭
I'll see you for supper.
好吧
Okay.
伙计们 你们看
Guys, guys look!
来到这里 来吧 来看看
Come here. Come on, come on look!
让我们去
Let's go.
你留守 直到我们回来
You stay guard over till we get back.
我想看看她能否发现这个陷阱
I wanna see if she's gonna figure out this booby trap.
是 看起来他们在那堆糖果周围又重新埋下了地雷
Yes. It seems they reburied their mines around that big pile of goodies.
她肯定能发现 不是吗？
She certainly figure it out, haven't she?
凯特尼斯
Katniss!
凯特尼斯 救命呀
凯特尼斯
Katniss! Help!
救命啊 救命啊
Help me! Help!
凯特尼斯
Katniss!
好了
It's okay.
你没事
You're okay.
You're alright.
你挺好的…看到了吗？
You're fine...see?
没关系
It's okay.
你没事
You're okay.
你炸毁他们的食物了吗？
Did you blow up the food?
所有的都被炸了
Every bit of it.
好
Good.
你一定要赢
You have to win.
好的
Okay.
在草地深处
Deep in the meadow.
在柳树下
Under the willow.
草做的床
A bed of grass.
柔软 绿色的枕头
A soft, green pillow.
放下你的头
Lay down your head.
闭上眼睛
And close your eyes.
不要杀她
Don't kill her.
你在创造一个杀人犯
You just create a murder.
看来 我已经得到一个了
It seems I've already got one.
我已经听到这个在11区的传闻了
I heard this rumors out on District 11.
这样可以从这里脱身
This could get away from here.
你想要什么？
What do you want?
那里怒气冲天 我知道你懂得如何处理它 你以前处理过
There are a lot of anger out there. I know you know how to handle a mod, you've done it before.
如果你不能让他们怕你 那就想办法让他们支持你
If you can't scare them. Give them something to root for.
比如？
Such as?
年轻的爱情
Young love.
你就像是一个失败者
So you were like an underdog.
每个人都喜欢失败者
Everyone likes an underdog.
我不喜欢
I don't.
死了多少个？
How many are dead?
10？11？12？
10? 11? 12?
呃…
Uh...
不是以个人名义 不
Not personally, no!
我有
I have.
很多失败者
Lots of underdogs.
也不太冷了
Not too cold too.
庄稼 矿
Row crops. Minerals.
我们需要的东西
Things we need.
有很多的失败者
There are lots of underdogs.
我想如果你能看到他们
And I think if you could see them.
你也不会支持他们
You would not root for them either.
不像你…
Unlike you...
小心点
Be careful.
贡者斗士们 注意了
Attention Tributes. Attention!
只有一个单一的胜利者的规则要求 被暂停了
The regulations required a single victor has been...suspended!
从现在开始 可以给两个胜利者加冕 只要他们都源于同一区
From now on, two victors maybe crowned if both originate from the same district.
这将是唯一的公告
This will be the only announcement.
天啊 皮塔
Oh my God! Peeta!
皮塔
Peeta!
嗨
Hi.
好啦
It's okay.
它是什么？
What was it?
剑
The sword.
它伤得很重
It's badly hurt.
它会没事的
It's gonna be fine.
凯特尼斯…
Katniss...
不
No!
我不会离开你
I'm not gonna leave you!
我不会那样做的
I'm not gonna do that.
为什么不呢？
Why not?
没有人会在这里找到你的
Nobody's gonna find you in here.
他们已经找到了我
They already found me.
我们去给你弄些药
We just get you some medicine.
他不能 他们不会给这么多伞投的
He can't. They don't give so much parachutes.
我们会想出一些办法
We'll figure something out.
比如什么？
Like what?
某些东西
Something.
是药吗？
Is that medicine?
不
No!
汤
Soup.
很美味
Nice taste.
你就喂一次？
Do you fed once?
我一直在想那件事
I think about that all the time.
我怎么会把面包丢给你
How I tossed you that bread.
皮塔
Peeta.
我应该去看你 我应该走出去到雨里
I should've gone to you. I should've just gone out to the rain.
你好热呀
You feel hot.
我记得我第一次见到你
I remember the first time I saw you.
你的头发是两个而不是一个辫子
Your hair was in two braids instead of one.
我还记得当你…
I remember when you...
你唱的就像老师说的那样简单
You sang in music as simply the teacher said.
谁知道你直接就停了那破歌
Who knows the pie song in your head shut straight up!
在那之后…
After that...
我每天看着你回家
I watched you going home everyday.
每一天
Everyday.
嗯 说点什么吧
Well, say something.
我不想说些什么
I'm not gonna say something.
你可以到这里来
You can come here.
求你了
Please.
如果我没有把它…
If I don't even make it.
贡者斗士们 请注意
Attention Tributes. Attention!
黎明时开始
Commencing Insuberance.
明天将在聚宝盆举行盛宴
There will be a feast tomorrow at the Curnocopia.
这将是极不平凡的盛会
This will be no ordinary occasion.
你们每个人都需要一些东西
Each of you needs something.
拼命地
Desperately.
我们计划是…
And we planned to be...
大方的东道主
generous hosts.
你还是坐着吧
You rather sit.
那是我们需要的 但是你不能走
That we needed and you can't walk.
答应我 你不要因为我而去冒生命的危险
Promise me, you'll not gonna risk your life for me.
我不会让你这么做的
I'm not gonna let you.
你会为我这么做吧？
You would do it for me.
不是吗？
Wouldn't you?
你为什么要这样做呢？
Why are you doing this?
皮塔
Peeta!
求你
Please.
留下来
Stay.
好吧
Okay.
我会留下来
I'll stay.
不
No!
小白脸在哪里？
Where's lover boy?
噢 我明白了
Oh I see.
你想要帮助他 是吗？
You're gonna help him right?
那是甜蜜的
That's sweet.
现在 这太糟糕了 你不能帮助你的小朋友了
Now, it's too bad you couldn't help your little friend.
那个小女孩…她叫什么名字？
That little girl...what was her name again?
芸香？
Rue?
是啊 我们杀了她
Yeah. Well we killed her.
现在…
And now...
我们会杀了你…
We're gonna kill you...
你杀了她吗？
You kill her?
不
No!
卡托
Cato!
喊她的名字
Shout her name!
只有这一次 十二区的
Just this time twelve.
为了芸香
For Rue!
皮塔
Peeta!
我拿到了
I got it.
我拿到药了
I got the medicine.
你怎么了？
What happened to you?
不 我不是 发生了什么事？
No, I'm not. What happened?
2区的女孩 她刺了一刀 我没事
The girl from two, she threw a knife. I'm okay.
你不应该去 你说过你不会去的
You shouldn't have gone. You said you aren't gonna go.
你病得严重了
You got worse.
你也用一些这个药吧
You get some of that too.
我没事
I'm okay.
感觉好多了
That feels better.
好啦
Okay.
你呢？
Are you?
我挺好
I'm okay.
不 来吧 你也需要它
No, come on. You need it too.
来吧
Come on.
哦
Oh.
你好多了
You're so much better.
噢 我的上帝 皮塔
Oh my God, Peeta.
我什么也感觉不到了
I couldn't feel anything.
我们可以回家了
We could go home.
我们知道 起飞
We know, took off.
是会待在聚宝盆
Right in the mouth of the Cornocopia.
他是不会去他不知道的地方的
He's not gonna go to places he doesn't know.
狐狸脸 她可能在任何地方
Fox face, she could be anywhere.
我们应该在这里打猎 我们没有食物了
We should probably hunt around here. We don't have any food left.
好吧 嗯 我会拿弓
Okay, uh, I'll take the bow.
我只是在开玩笑
I'm just kidding.
皮塔？
Peeta?
你还好吗？
Are you okay?
我听到了炮声
I hear the cannon.
这是有毒植物 皮塔
That's nightlock Peeta!
你一分钟前差点死了
You will be dead in a minute.
我…我不知道
I...I didn't know.
你吓死我了
You scare me to death.
你这该死的
Damn you.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我甚至不知道 她在跟着我
I don't even knew, she was following me.
她很聪明
She's clever.
太聪明了
Too clever.
你在干什么？
What're you doing?
也许卡托也喜欢浆果？
Maybe Cato likes berries too?
几点了？
What time is it?
下午吧
A little afternoon.
为什么这么黑？
Why is it so dark?
必须尽快结束
Must be in a hurry to end it.
准备好了 露西亚？
Ready Lusia?
哦 在这呢 先生
Oh right here sir!
太好了
That's great.
你能把那个放到中间吗？
Can you put that in the middle?
能
Sure.
就是这样
That's it.
就是这样 太棒了
That's it. Excellent.
你听到了吗？
Did you hear that?
那是什么？
What was that?
它是终曲
It's the finale.
走吧
Let's go.
在这里
Here.
继续
Go on.
放箭呀
Shoot.
我俩都掉下去 你就赢了
And we both go down and you'd win.
继续呀
Go on.
反正是死
Dead anyway.
我总是想喝酒
I always want a drink.
现在到不想了
Until not so now.
是如何形成的呢？这就是你想要的吗？
How's that? Is that what you want?
呵呵
Huh!
不
No!
我仍然可以做到这一点
I can still do this.
多杀一个
One more kill.
这是我唯一知道该怎么做的事
It's the only thing I know how to do.
给我们区带来骄傲
Bring pride to the district.
不管做什么
Not that it matters.
求你…
Please...
请注意 贡者斗士们
Attention. Attention Tributes.
规则有一点变化
There has been a slight rule change.
以前的那个允许来自同一地区有两个胜利者的条款已被废除
The previous provision allowing for two victors from the same district has been revoked.
只有一个胜利者允许加冕 祝好运
Only one victor maybe crowned. Goodluck.
好运永远属于你
And may the odds be ever in your favor.
来吧
Go ahead.
我们每个人都应该回家
One of us should go home!
我们中的一个必须死 他们一定要有他们的胜利者
One of us has to die. They had to have their victor.
不
No.
他们不是这样做的
They don't.
他们为什么要呢？
Why should they?
不
No!
相信我
Trust me.
一起吗？
Together?
在一起
Together.
好吧
Okay.
一…
One...
二…
Two...
三…
Three...
住手
Stop!
女士们 先生们
Ladies and gentlemen.
我来介绍…
May I present the winners...
第74届饥饿游戏的胜利者…
of the 74th Annual Hunger Games.
他们不喜欢和你在一起
They're not happy with you.
为什么呢？因为我们没死吗？
Why? Because we didn't die?
因为你把他们看透了
Because you showed them all.
嗯…
Well...
对不起我没按照他们计划的那样去做
I'm sorry it didn't go the way they planned.
你知道我也不是很喜欢和他们在一起
You know I'm not very happy with them either.
凯特尼斯…
Katniss...
这是认真的
This is serious.
不只是为你
Not just for you.
他们不採取这样的事情掉以轻心
They don't take this things lightly.
你说你情不自禁
You say you couldn't help yourself.You're so in love
你是如此的爱这个男孩以至于黑暗都无法用最…
with this boy that the dark have not with the most...
不可思议啊…
Unthinkable...
如果不能和他在一起 你宁可死… 你明白吗？
You rather die...than not be with him you understand?
你是什么感觉？
How did you feel?
当你在河边发现他的时候？
When you found him by the river?
我觉得我是世界上最幸福的人
I felt like the happiest person in the world.
我无法想像没有他的生活
I couldn't imagine life without him.
皮塔 你呢？
And what about you Peeta?
该死的 她只是救了我的命
Damn, she just saved my life.
我们拯救了对方
We saved each other.
女士们 先生们
Ladies and gentlemen.
12区的明星
The star cross lovers of District 12, this
今年第74届饥饿游戏的胜利者
years victors of the 74th Annual Hunger Games.
祝贺你
Congratulations.
谢谢
Thank you.
一个多么可爱的胸针
What a lovely pin.
谢谢你 这是来自我的区的
Thank you, it's from my district.
他们一定会为你感到骄傲的
They must be very proud of you.
我们回去后会发生什么？
So what happens when we get back?
我不知道
I don't know.
我想我会努力忘记
I guess I may try to forget.
我不想忘记
I don't wanna forget.
《饥饿游戏》